MANU DWIVEDI

Full-Stack Web Developer

PERSONAL PROFILE

I have over 6 years of experience in various growth start-ups and consulting firms. I specialize in frameworks across the stack including React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, git, Linux and Docker. I like to learn and teach something every day

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Conducted training sessions in Ruby/Rails in a FinTech startup
- Conducted workshop on Git for Computer Society of India
- Industry mentor, Smart India Hackathon 2 years in a row
 - Second runner-up, Swiss-Re IBM hackathon, Bangalore

GET IN TOUCH

Email: manu29.d@gmail.com
Portfolio: https://manu29d.github.io
LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/manu29d/

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

B.Tech, NIT, Trichy (2009-2013)

WORK HISTORY

Senior Software Engineer

Curve Tomorrow, Feb 2017 to Apr 2019

Curve Tomorrow is a technology consultant for healthcare related products based out of MCRI, Royal Children's Hospital, Melbourne, Australia

- · Team Lead, Rails developer and Architect, Sleepwake API
- · Ruby on Rails and Angular developer, Auslan+
- Domain expert and developer, rails base api and CI/CD deployments
- · React developer, Macuject

Senior Software Engineer

Talentica Software, Oct 2014 to Jan 2016

Talentica Software is a product development outsourcing firm targeting start-ups. I joined as a junior developer and was promoted in 6 months

- Ruby on Rails developer, evvnt
- Consulting expert, Javascript and Backbone JS, HomeUnion
- · Google Maps API and Backbone developer, HomeUnion Maps
- · Angular Developer, Culture Machine

Software Engineer

Kreatio Software, June 2013 to Sept 2014

Kreatio is a SaaS aimed at publishers, publishing houses and journalists

- · Ruby on Rails developer, code rewrite from Rails 2 to Rails 4
- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Team Lead and Rails developer, new vertical for Smart Schools
- · Conducted training sessions on Ruby, git and Rails

Freelance Consultant

Project Management, Angular, React, Rails, Django

- Business and Product consultant for Mouve Shoes, retail and online shoe store from under-priviliged handicraft artisans
- Product Lead for Terra Analytics, B2B real estate due diligence engine
- Project Strategy Consultant for Data Science Pipeline and Deployment of microservices for Tapchief, platform for consulting and freelancing
- Product developer for Traco, B2B F&B supply chain management
- Product developer for Paintcollar, B2B2C merchandising platform for digital artists, media houses and content creators
- $\hbox{\bf \cdot} \ \mbox{Web developer for KingFisher \#FlipToTheGoodTimes campaign through SpectraVR} \\$
- Web developer for data visualization and monitoring/reporting platform for data science infrastructure at 3LOQ, B2B data science solution for banks
- Lead, Architect and Design for Tailor Trendy, e-commerce for customized women apparel